<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Gifted Space - Tz</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/tz.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2024-08-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>The Power of Focus: A Reflection on H. Spencer Lewis's Wisdom</title><link href="/posts/2024/Aug/10/the-power-of-focus-a-reflection-on-h-spencer-lewiss-wisdom/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-08-10T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2024-08-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tz</name></author><id>tag:None,2024-08-10:/posts/2024/Aug/10/the-power-of-focus-a-reflection-on-h-spencer-lewiss-wisdom/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Reflecting on H. Spencer Lewis's insight into the transformative power of focused thought and its impact on creative and efficient thinking.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In a world filled with distractions, the ability to concentrate the mind on a single point is a skill of immense power. As H. Spencer Lewis wisely observed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Once we come to know that by the concentration of the mind on one point, on one principle, on one desire, a power is radiated to that point with creative nature and demonstrative abilities, we will think more carefully, more constructively and more efficiently."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This statement is a reminder of the transformative potential that lies within focused thought. When we channel our mental energy toward a singular purpose or principle, we ignite a creative force that not only shapes our thoughts but also manifests in the world around us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concentration&lt;/strong&gt; is more than just a practice; it is a path to &lt;strong&gt;constructive and efficient thinking&lt;/strong&gt;. It teaches us to direct our mental faculties with intention, avoiding the scattered nature of an unfocused mind. By honing in on what truly matters, we unlock the power to create, to demonstrate, and to bring our desires to fruition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we reflect on these words, let us consider how we can apply this wisdom in our daily lives. What is the one point, the one principle, or the one desire that you need to focus on? By aligning your thoughts and energy towards it, you may discover a new level of efficiency and creativity that drives you closer to your goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a moment today to meditate on this insight and see where the power of focus can lead you.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="misc"></category><category term="mysteries"></category></entry></feed>